# 7huo **Su**

# Research Scientist in Computer Vision and Multimodal Learning, Huawei Suomi Finland

github.com/hellozhuo Blogs:zhuogege1943.com/blogs

I am a Research Scientist at Huawei Helsinki R&D Center in Finland, working on computer vision and multimodal learning. I am also a PostDoc (part-time) at the University of Oulu in Generative AI. Before that, I defended my thesis in October 2023. My thesis topic is Efficient Representation Learning for Computer Vision, towards building real-time and compact deep learning models.

Interests: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer vision, Multimodal Learning, Math, Coding

# 🖳 Programming

# Tools/Frameworks



Python Matlab C/C++/C++.NET Pytorch Linux Git vim

- > English (fluent)
- > Chinese (native)
- > Finnish (survival)



### EXPERIENCE

### Research Scientist (Huawei Suomi, Finland)

SEPTEMBER 2024 - PRESENT

In a team with experts in LLM, computer vision, generative AI, and multimodal learning. My duties include 1. Developing multimodal AI models for building global abuse detection and prevention systems. 2. Profiling and optimizing the latency consumptions of models for on-device inference, ensuring real-time performance while maintaining industry-level accuracy. 2. R&D though dataset and architecture iterations for the on-device models.

On-device Model | Computer Vision | Multimodal Learning

Postdoc in Generative AI and Multimodal Learning (Oulu University, Finland) NOVEMBER 2023 - PRESENT (PART-TIME NOW)

I worked on generative models based on stable diffusion, GAN, and multimodal learning. I am also supervising PhD and Master students, as well as giving lectures on deep learning basics.

Diffusion Models | Face Editing | Multimodal Learning

### Machine Learning Intern (Intel Lab, Germany. 7 months)

SEPTEMBER 2022 - MARCH 2023

I worked with Matthias Müller at Intel Lab, Germany, on building efficient computer vision networks. We achieved a good performance in terms of speed and accuracy on light hardware for real-time salient object detection.

Computer Vision Efficient Neural Networks Real-time Salient Object Detection

#### Visiting Researcher (University of Amsterdam. 6 months)

OCTOBER 2021 - MARCH 2022

☑ ELLIS PhD & Postdoc Program ☑ AMLab

I visited AMLab under the ELLIS PhD & Postdoc Program. There, I worked with Prof. Max Welling, on the topic of "Binary SO(3) Equivariant Graph Neural Networks". A paper was published at the International conference on 3D vision 2022.

Graph Neural Networks | Rotation Equivariant | Network Binarization

#### Software Engineer (Samsung R&D Institute China-Beijing. 3 months)

MAY 2018 - JULY 2018

I worked in the Machine learning group, on Optical Character Recognition.

Computer Vision Optical Character Recognition

#### Software Engineer Intern (Aihujing.com, China. 4 months)

JANUARY 2018 - APRIL 2018

I worked as a computer vision intern, on Optical Character Recognition.

Computer Vision Optical Character Recognition



# **EDUCATION**

### October 2023

#### Ph.D, Computer Science and Engineering, University of Oulu, Finland

October 2018

Thesis: LBP Inspired Efficient Deep Convolutional Neural Networks for Visual Representation Learning Supervisor : Dr. Li Liu ; Opponent : Prof. Karen Eguiazarian ; Custos : Prof. Matti Pietikäinen Computer Vision Network compression Binary neural networks Efficient Graph neural networks

# March 2018

## M.Sc, Automation Science and Electrical Engineering, Beihang University, China

#### September 2015 Thesis: Salient Object Detection for Single Images

Supervisors: Prof. Hong Zheng, Prof. Baochang Zhang

GPA: 3.24/4.0

Image processing | Salient object detection | Machine learning

# June 2015

## B.Sc, Automation Science and Electrical Engineering, Beihang University, China

September 2011

Topic: Pattern Recognition

GPA: 3.68/4.0

Pattern recognition | Machine learning



# 🗐 Papers (first author)

- 1. Zhuo Su et al. "Boosting Convolutional Neural Networks with Middle Spectrum Grouped Convolution", IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems (TNNLS), 2024
  - d pdf pdf github.com/hellozhuo/msgc
- 2. Zhuo Su et al. "Lightweight Pixel Difference Networks for Efficient Visual Representation Learning", IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), 2023
- 3. Zhuo Su et al. "Pixel Difference Networks for Efficient Edge Detection", IEEE/CVF International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2021 (oral presentation)
  - d pdf github.com/hellozhuo/pidinet
- 4. Zhuo Su et al. "Dynamic Group Convolution for Accelerating Convolutional Neural Networks", European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020 (spotlight presentation)
  - d pdf og github.com/hellozhuo/dgc
- 5. Zhuo Su et al. "BIRD: Learning Binary and Illumination Robust Descriptor for Face Recognition", British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC), 2019
  - pdf pdf github.com/hellozhuo/bird-descriptor
- 6. Zhuo Su et al. "SVNet: Where SO(3) Equivariance Meets Binarization on Point Cloud Representation", IEEE International Conference on 3D Vision (3DV), 2022
  - d pdf github.com/hellozhuo/svnet
- 7. Zhuo Su et al. "From Local Binary Patterns to Pixel Difference Networks for Efficient Visual Representation Learning", Scandinavian Conference on Image Analysis (SCIA), 2023 **☑** pdf
- 8. Zhuo Su et al. "Rapid Salient Object Detection with Difference Convolutional Neural Networks" (TPAMI, in Major revision)

# Papers (co-author)

- 1. Chao Xiao et al. Zhuo Su et al. "Highly Efficient and Unsupervised Framework for Moving Object Detection in Satellite Videos", IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (TPAMI), 2024
- 2. Huali Xu et al. Zhuo Su et al. "Enhancing Information Maximization with Distance-Aware Contrastive Learning for Source-Free Cross-Domain Few-Shot Learning", IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (TIP), 2024
- 3. Zitong Yu et al. Zhuo Su et al. "Searching central difference convolutional networks for face anti-spoofing", IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2020
- 4. Wanxia Deng, Zhuo Su et al. "Deep ladder reconstruction classification network for unsupervised domain adaptation", Pattern Recognition Letters (PRL), 2021
- 5. Jiehua Zhang, Zhuo Su, Li Liu, "Median Pixel Difference Convolutional Network for Robust Face Recognition", British Machine Vision Conference (BMVC), 2021
- 6. Jiehua Zhang, Zhuo Su et al. "Dynamic Binary Neural Network by learning channel-wise thresholds", The International Conference on Acoustics, Speech, & Signal Processing (ICASSP), 2022



# Scientific Contributions

#### Teaching Assistant, University of Oulu

2018 - PRESENT

I have been working as the teaching assistant of the course "Deep Learning" in University of Oulu in the past years.

Deep Learning Network Compression Pytorch

INVITED REVIEWER 2019 - PRESENT

Journals

TPAMI, TIP, TMM, TCSVT, Neurocomputing, PRL, CVIU, TOMM

Conferences

CVPR, ICCV, ECCV, ICME, ICASSP, ACMMM, AAAI, ACCV, ICPR, PRCV